[ 
{"question": "Which Union Ministry is set to launch a program for development of eastern states called ‘Purvodaya’?", 
"options": ["A. Ministry of Road Transport and Highways", "B. Ministry of Agriculture & Farmers Welfare", "C. Ministry of Development of North Eastern Region", "D. Ministry of Steel"], "answer": "D. Ministry of Steel"}
, {"question": "Raisina Dialogue is jointly organized by Ministry of External Affairs and which foreign policy and strategy think tank of India?", 
"options": ["A. Observer Research Foundation", "B. Indian Council of World Affairs", "C. Centre for Policy Research", "D. Vivekananda International Foundation"], "answer": "A. Observer Research Foundation"}
, {"question": "Ministry of Rural Development (MoRD) has recently signed an MoU with which of the following organizations?", 
"options": ["A. World Bank", "B. Bill and Melinda Gates Foundation", "C. Asian Development Bank", "D. BRICS Bank"], "answer": "B. Bill and Melinda Gates Foundation"}
, {"question": "The online monitoring portal named ‘GATI’ was recently launched by which Union Ministry?", 
"options": ["A. Ministry of Road Transport and Highways", "B. Ministry of Micro, Small and Medium Enterprises", "C. Ministry of Consumer Affairs, Food and Public Distribution", "D. Ministry of Agriculture & Farmers Welfare"], "answer": "A. Ministry of Road Transport and Highways"}
, {"question": "National Institute of Rural Development and Panchayati Raj (NIRDPR) has recently partnered with which global organisation to establish a ‘Communication Resource Unit’?", 
"options": ["A. World Bank", "B. UNICEF", "C. UNESCO", "D. International Monetary Fund"], "answer": "B. UNICEF"}
, {"question": "India’s first and biggest walk-through aviary with over 100 species of birds, was recently inaugurated in which city?", 
"options": ["A. Mumbai", "B. Guwahati", "C. Bengaluru", "D. Thiruvananthapuram"], "answer": "A. Mumbai"}
, {"question": "Recently, the Supreme Court of India upheld the Scheduled Castes and the Scheduled Tribes (Prevention of Atrocities) Amendment Act. When was the original act of 1989 amended?", 
"options": ["A. 2016", "B. 2017", "C. 2018", "D. 2019"], "answer": "C. 2018"}
, {"question": "What is the term of the 22nd Law Commission of India, recently approved by the Union Cabinet of India?", 
"options": ["A. Two years", "B. Three years", "C. Five years", "D. Six years"], "answer": "B. Three years"}
, {"question": "Which state hiked the MLAs’ Local Area Development Fund to Rs.3 Crore per year?", 
"options": ["A. Maharashtra", "B. Punjab", "C. Uttar Pradesh", "D. Odisha"], "answer": "C. Uttar Pradesh"}
, {"question": "Which state government recently abolished the policy of granting service extension to its employees after retirement?", 
"options": ["A. Odisha", "B. Rajasthan", "C. Punjab", "D. Uttar Pradesh"], "answer": "C. Punjab"}
, {"question": "’Chapchar Kut’ is a popular festival of which Indian state/ UT?", 
"options": ["A. Madhya Pradesh", "B. Assam", "C. Mizoram", "D. Arunachal Pradesh"], "answer": "C. Mizoram"}
, {"question": "Who is the Chairperson of the recently reconstituted National Platform for Disaster Risk Reduction (NPDRR)?", 
"options": ["A. Union Home Minister", "B. Union Defence Minister", "C. Union Environment Minister", "D. Union Finance Minister"], "answer": "A. Union Home Minister"}
, {"question": "Which state launched an initiative called ‘Safe homes’ to provide safe accommodation to inter-caste and inter-religious couples?", 
"options": ["A. Andhra Pradesh", "B. Kerala", "C. Karnataka", "D. Tamil Nadu"], "answer": "B. Kerala"}
, {"question": "Who is the head of the Delimitation Commission recently set up to redraw the Lok Sabha and assembly constituencies in Jammu and Kashmir, and 4 North-Eastern states?", 
"options": ["A. Ranjana Prakash Desai", "B. Arjan Kumar Sikri", "C. Adarsh Kumar Goel", "D. Jasti Chelameswar"], "answer": "A. Ranjana Prakash Desai"}
, {"question": "‘Shaadi Bhagya Scheme’, which was making news recently, was a scheme of which state?", 
"options": ["A. Bihar", "B. Odisha", "C. Karnataka", "D. Maharashtra"], "answer": "C. Karnataka"}
, {"question": "The project to construct a new Integrated Check Post (ICP) at Sabroom has been approved. The town Sabroom is located in which North-eastern state?", 
"options": ["A. Assam", "B. Tripura", "C. Nagaland", "D. Meghalaya"], "answer": "B. Tripura"}
, {"question": "‘Mo Jeeban (My Life)’ is an initiative of which Indian state to advise people to stay indoors amid the coronavirus pandemic?", 
"options": ["A. West Bengal", "B. Odisha", "C. Telangana", "D. Bihar"], "answer": "B. Odisha"}
, {"question": "After the recent curbs on exports of diagnostic kits by the Indian Government, an exporter will have to get a licence from which authority for out-bound shipments?", 
"options": ["A. Directorate General of Foreign Trade (DGFT)", "B. Directorate General of Trade Remedies (DGTR)", "C. Directorate General of Commercial Intelligence and Statistics", "D. Department of Health Research"], "answer": "A. Directorate General of Foreign Trade (DGFT)"}
, {"question": "National Commission for Women (NCW) launches WhatsApp number to report cases of domestic violence. Where is the Headquarters of NCW located?", 
"options": ["A. Lucknow", "B. New Delhi", "C. Nagpur", "D. Mumbai"], "answer": "B. New Delhi"}
, {"question": "Which is the first state to bring its migrant labourers, after lock-down, through the Special Shramik Trains run by Ministry of Railways?", 
"options": ["A. Jharkhand", "B. Kerala", "C. Uttar Pradesh", "D. Rajasthan"], "answer": "A. Jharkhand"}
]